VICTOR WILLIAMS

Full Stack Software Engineer

444 N 4th Street, 401 Philadelphia, PA 19123 484-895-5489 vaporjawn.dev/

vrwilliams719@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Full stack software developer with strong analytical skills and proficiency in mathematics. Individual with ability to follow established procedures and work under little or no supervision. Bringing expertise in writing full-stack code to support multiple platforms, including web, android, and iOS, and a solid grasp of MVC, data structures, and object-oriented designs. Full software development life cycle experience and team management experience.

EDUCATION -

Temple University,

Philadelphia, PA May 2019

- Bachelor of Arts: Computer Science and Criminal Justice Certificate: Computer Security
- Studied the subjects of Discrete Mathematics, Differential Calculus, Data Structures, Algorithms, and Operating Systems within the Computer Science Curriculum

ACTIVITIES -

Temple University
Development Team – Eboard,
Computer Science Tutor (TU),
(ACM) Association for
Computing Machinery,
Scrum Alliance,
(MLH) Major League Hacking,
PennApps at UPenn,
Alliance for Minority
Participation in STEM.
The Odyssey Online,
Let's Get Ready SAT Prep
Program,

Owlchestra, Violinist

EXPERIENCE

Context Capital Partners

Full Stack Application Developer

June 2020 – Present

- Involved in writing application level code to interact with Web Services using Ajax, JSON, and XML. Deploying and testing features to the Azure Cloud
- Developed and tested a web application with successful production launch
- Created and maintained fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment
- Assisted in repository management
- Skills: React, Git, TypeScript, Integromat, Azure, SCRUM, JavaScript, C#

BankMobile

Jan. 2020 – June 2020

Full Stack Software Engineer

- Architecture and development of REST services powered web-based SaaS application
- Web, iOS, and Android applications
- Worked in scrum process attending daily stand up and completing tasks in sprints
- A hand in both web and mobile development
- Collaborated on a large scale of developers based around the globe
- Skills: .NET, Xamarin, Angular.JS, C#, RESTfulAPI, Azure, SCSS, SQL, Swift, JavaScript, JSON, Visual Studio

AmeriCorps

July. 2019 - Dec. 2019

Information Technology Manager / Web Developer

- · Refined and improved the existing documentation within the system
- Reduced number of open tickets by 87% by prioritizing all open issues
- Updated several School District websites from AngularJS to ReactJS
- Managed a tech team and all technology in Taggart John H. School
- Skills: Angular.JS, API, Cloud, JSON, HTML5, CSS, Vue, MongoDB

ORGANIZATIONS

Github Developer Program, Google Analytics, HackNY, TUDev, MLH Fellows, AmeriCorps, HackRU Let's Get Ready, Big Brother Big Sister, ACM, PennApps

BitGamer

Nov. 2018 - Nov. 2019

Full Stack Developer / Tournament Organizer

- Developed a tournament hosting web application along with a small team
- Lead a geographically distributed team with large and small scale projects
- Wrote a series of technical documents to help speed up new engineer onboarding
- Managed social media for the company and performed quality analysis
- Skills: React.js, Node.js, RESTfulAPI, AWS, Visual Studio, Java, Python, HTML5

CrystalFruit

Dec. 2016 - Mar. 2019

Full Stack Developer

- Implemented solutions using Agile (SCRUM) methodology
- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data
- Lead a team of 3 software engineers, creating roadmap definitions, established engineering best practices and mentored other members of the team
- Maintained and updated websites upon request per client, held meetings with team and end users to discuss product planning
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications and software
- Skills: Bootstrap, Vue.js, ASP.NET MVC MongoDB, Git, API, PHP, Vue, Ruby, HTML5, CSS, Go, Node.js, JSON